Nicolas Hery

Montreal, Quebec hi@nicolashery.com http://nicolashery.com

Web developer with a background in applied mathematics and a thing for building well-designed web applications with great user experience that solve data-driven business problems or simply make people's lives better.

Experience

Sep 2015 - Web Developer
Present Busbud, Montreal

Jan 2015 - Web Developer
Aug 2015 - Freelance, Montreal

- · Worked with a startup to build the prototype of a solution that helps small businesses manage their data
- Built the interface of an MVP used to explore a large database of industry data and visualize key metrics

Oct 2013 - Contract Web Developer Tidepool, Paris & Montreal

- Worked remotely for the non-profit organization whose mission is to reduce the burden of Type-1 Diabetes
- · Helped build the core platform which synchronizes diabetes data from many medical devices
- Built with a small team of developers the MVP version of Blip, a web-based data visualization tool

Jan 2010 -May 2013

Data Analyst

FreshDirect, New York

- · Built a web application that aggregates data from multiple systems and generates a demand forecasting Excel sheet
- Implemented a pilot program that uses an innovative cloud-based product forecasting service
- · Wrote and implemented several scripts to transform and load data, as well as automate redundant tasks

Oct 2009 – Dec 2009

Student Project

Google, New York

- Managed a team of students from Columbia University on a project for Google's Operations Research group
- · Used Python to simulate job scheduling in data centers and optimize the algorithm to decrease power consumption

May 2009 – Jul 2009

Intern Consultant

Cylad Consulting, France

- Worked with a team of consultants for Airbus on the project planning of the Airbus 350 XWB
- · Developed an Excel VBA tool to create Gantt charts from the main scheduling platform's data

Education

2009 - 2010

Columbia University

MS in Operations Research, New York

· Selected coursework: Deterministic and Stochastic Models, Corporate Finance, Entrepreneurship, Supply Chain

2007 - 2009

Ecole Centrale de Nantes

MS in Industrial Engineering, France

Selected coursework: Probability and Statistics, Calculus, Economics, International Strategy

Skills

Best at JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js

Good at Python, MongoDB, MySQL, Photoshop

Influences

People Rich Hickey, Mike Bostock, Paul Irish, John Foreman, Eric Ries, & more

Products GitHub, Trello, Google Apps, 37signals, Square, & more

Interests

web apps, design, user experience, data visualization, scientific computing, running, swimming, guitar, travelling, good wine, good scotch, good company